Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series II. Correspondence - General/Professional
  - Szilard, Leo, Atomic Scientists of Chicago, Inc., to R.R.W., C. U., re revised "Letter to Stalin" [cc, signed], letter to Editors and article [mc], 11/20/1947 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Tape, Gerald F., AEC, from R.R.W., C. U., re cost of proposed 200 Gev proton synchrotron at UCB [tls], note on recto [am], 10/4/1965-not sent (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tape, Gerald F., AEC, from R.R.W., C. U., re cost of proposed 200 Gev proton synchrotron, suggested ways to lessen expenses [cc], paper "Comments on the High Energy Physics Program in the United States" [mc], Enclosure A "Higher energy accelerators" [mc], "The 200 Bev Synchrotron" [cc], 1 figure [mc], 10/19/1965 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tape, Gerald F., to R.R.W., re thanks for congratulations on winning Fermi Award [als], 1/8/1988 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tarantola, A., Universitè Pierre et Marie Curie, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re paper "Neutrino exploration of the Earth" [tls], 3/5/1984 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, from R.R.W., re manuscript for publication, concerns investigation of focusing actions of cyclotron [cc], 12/21/1937 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, to R.R.W., UCB, re receipt of "Magnetic and Electrostatic Focusing in the Cyclotron" [postcard], 12/27/1937 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, to R.R.W., UCB, re article, send figures to NYC address [tls], 1/10/1938 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., University of Minnesota, from R.R.W., re paper being submitted for publication in The Physical Review [cc], 6/28/1938 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re manuscript of paper by R.R.W. and Edward C. Creutz on "Proton-Proton Scattering at 8 Mev," needs abstract [tls], 11/16/1946 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, from R.R.W., re submitting paper "Proton-Proton Scattering at 8 Mev" for publication in The Physical Review [cc], 12/9/1946 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, from R.R.W., re submitting paper "Range Straggling, and Multiple Scattering of Fast Protons" for publication in The Physical Review [cc], 1/28/1947 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, from R.R.W., re submitting letter for publication in The Physical Review [cc]; receipt from J. T. T., for letter [postcard], 2/21/1947 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, from R.R.W., re paper "Directional Properties of Fission Neutrons" [cc], 3/31/1947 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Tate, John T., The Physical Review, from R.R.W., re paper "Time for Fission" [cc], 4/11/1947 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Taylor, G. Rattray, BBC, to Donald Mainwaring, C. U., re help filming Professor Gold and work on lunar surface, R.R.W. in double role as scientist and sculptor, Professor Steward and work on growth of plants from single cells [phc], 3/16/1965 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Harold, National Research Council on Peace Strategy, to R.R.W., C. U., re endorsement of statement by Bernard Feld and David Inglis on test-ban treaty [tls]; reply, 4/29/1963 [cc], 4/25/1963 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Holman, Library of State Medical Association of Texas, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re request for copies of article "Radiological Use of Fast Protons" [postcard], 11/27/1946 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, I. E., Norton Company, to E. P. Wigner, Princeton University, re information about boron carbide [tls], 1/29/1941 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Joseph H., Princeton University, to "Robert J. Wilson," Ithaca, re panel report [tls], report [phc], 6/4/1984 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Lauriston S., National Bureau of Standards, to R.R.W., C. U., re invitation to serve on sub-committee of National Committee on Radiation Protection, "Heavy Ionizing Particles (Neutrons, Protons, and Heavier)" [tls]; reply, 6/13/1947 [cc], 5/23/1947 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Lauriston S., Commission on Radiological Units, Standards and Protection, to W. V. Maynoord, Royal Cancer Hospital, London, re recommendations on Radiological Units [mc], report [mc], 2/11/1949 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Lloyd W., AAPT, to "Dear Fellow Physics Teacher," re becoming a member [mc], 12/28/1945 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Taylor, Lloyd W., AAPT, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re welcome to Association [postcard], 12/3/1946 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Teem, John M., Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy (AURA), to R.R.W., Fermilab, re appreciation for services as member of AURA Visiting Committee for Kitt Peak National Observatory/Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory [tls], 5/15/1980 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Telegdi, Val, L., CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re relocating Fermi's grave to Santa Croce church in Florence, Italy [pls], note on recto [am], 10/1/1992 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Teller, Edward, University of California, Livermore, to R.R.W., C. U., re meeting to discuss physics problems in Sherwood program [tls], 10/20/1958 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Teller, Edward, University of California, Livermore, to R.R.W., C. U., re previous meeting [tls], 9/30/1959 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Teller, Edward, University of California, Livermore, to "Distribution," re Sherwood Program questions on "Confinement Time in the Mirror Machine," and "Electron Cyclotron Radiation" [mc], 10/9/1959 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Teller, Edward, Berkeley, Calif., to Jeffery Cohelan, Congress of the United States, re negotiations in Moscow and atmospheric tests [phc], 7/19/1963 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Teller, Edward, Hoover Institution, to Victor Weisskopf, C. U., re material he is sending to Wall Street Journal in response to Sudoplatov articles, urges V. W. to write in support of Bohr, E. T. writing in support of Fermi [phc], paper "Scientists and Spies" [phc], 5/5/1994 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Tessmer, Carl F., to "Surgeon, FEC and Chief, PH&W," re Plan for use of ABCC Facilities and Personnel in the Event of a Military Necessity [mc], personnel roster [mc], 7/7/1950 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Tessmer, Carl F., to Herman S. Wigodsky, Committee on Atomic Casualties, re progress of surveys in Japan [mc], 5/1/1950 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Tessmer, Carl F., to Herman S. Wigodsky, Committee on Atomic Casualties, re progress of surveys in Japan [mc], 6/2/1950 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Therrien, Ann, Columbia University to R.R.W., C. U., re DOE contract, summer budget [tls], 2/2/1984 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thomas, Kenneth M., Brobeck Corporation, to Dr. Raymond Kjellberg, Massachusetts General Hospital, re business plan for MAC, procedures [pl], 6/5/1987 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, no first name, Moscow, to Secretary of State, re Professor Emelyanov, (two sections) [thc, phc], unidentified, to Harry S. Traynor, 3/17/1960 [thermal copy, phc], 3/16/1960 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Emily, Harvard University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re talk "Architecture at Fermilab" [pl], 11/30/1993 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Emily, Iowa State University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re request for essay for The Architecture of Science [pl], 11/5/1994 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Emily, Iowa State University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re request for essay for The Architecture of Science [pl]; reply, 12/17/1994 [pl], vita [pi], corrections on recto [am], 11/30/1994 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Emily, Iowa State University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re receipt of essay for The Architecture of Science [als], 1/9/1995 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Emily, Iowa State University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re receipt of illustrations, captions, and disc file for essay for The Architecture of Science [pl], 3/27/1995 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Emily, Iowa State University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re submission of manuscript, The Architecture of Science to M. I. T. Press for consideration [pl], 5/12/1995 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Thompson, Grace, University of Chicago, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re form showing receipt of 1 hyper-vac 20, Cenco pump, returned to R.R.W. on 12/30/1942 [tls], note on verso [am], 3/6/1943 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Thorndike, Edward H., University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re report describing program of research planned for Rochester 10 GeV accelerator [tls], 10/28/1966 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Tichio, Harold K., UCLA, to R.R.W., C. U., re planned experiment to measure transition curves of electron showers in materials of intermediate and high Z, would appreciate any information on Monte Carlo electron shower calculations [tls]; reply, 12/15/1953 [cc], 12/10/1953 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Tigner, Maury, C. U., to Simpson Linke, C. U., re proposal to open communications between Electrical Engineering and LNS, brief personal resumé [cc], 9/12/1966 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Tigner, Maury, from R.R.W., C. U., re Magnetic Collars for SSC Magnets, draft, 3/4/1986 [al], 2nd draft, 3/18/1986 [phc]; reply 3/28/[1986] [als], "Magnetic Collars for SSC Magnets" [phc], 3/18/1986 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Tigner, Maury, to Special Commission on the Future of the NSF, re support for NSF [pl], 10/10/1992 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Tigner, Maury: David G. Cassel, C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., celebration to recognize Maury Tigner [pls], 1/24/1995 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Time Magazine, Editor, from R.R.W., Los Alamos, re spectre of nuclear energy [cc], 9/28/1945 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Tinlot, John H., University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re accelerator use [thc]; reply, 5/29/1963 [cc], 5/20/1963 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Tinlot, John H., University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re accelerator use, requests visit [tls], 6/12/1963 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Tinlot, John H., Rochester, to R.R.W., re confirmation of visit [tls], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Tinlot, John H., University of Rochester, to R.R.W., re plans for accelerator use, hopes to see him in Dubna [tls]; reply, 7/24/1964 [cc], 7/13/1964 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Titterton, Ernest W., Australian National University, to R.R.W., C. U., re invitation to speak on Elementary Particles [tls]; reply, 5/14/1953 [cc], 3/12/1953 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Tobias, C. A., Berkeley, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re request for copy of "Radiological Use of Fast Protons" [postcard], note on verso [am]; 2nd card, 12/16/1946 [postcard], 12/14/1946 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Tobias, C. A., UCB, from R.R.W., re Oberlin conference [cc], 5/12/1950 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Tobias, Cornelius A., UCB, to R.R.W., C. U., re report on human work done with the high-energy protons of cyclotron [tls], 9/28/1955 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Todorovich, Miro M., Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy, to "Dear Colleague," re Shoreham Plan [phc, signed], 9/23/1988 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Todres, Irving, Montreal, to R.R.W., C. U., re article "Electron Synchrotron Starts Work this Summer" [printed form, signed], 11/5/1954 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Toll, John S., FAS, to Mrs. R. R. Fleischbein, Washington, D. C., re distributing press release, distribution list [cc], memo re distribution list, 5/15/1963 [mc], 5/13/1963 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re preliminary list of FAS committee members and FAS National Committee chairmen [tls], 5/14/1963 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., University of Maryland, from R.R.W., re conference on Transition to Peacetime Economy [cc], Sanford Gottlieb, SANE, to R.R.W., 1/10/1964, re SANE [thc]; reply to S. G., 1/31/1964 [cc], 1/31/1964 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., University of Maryland, from R.R.W., re letter to Harold Green on subject of improving communications with Congressman Elliott in Select Committee on Government Research [cc], 1/29/1964, Dr. Harold P. Green, FAS, to R.R.W., re letter to Congressman Elliott [tls], C. E., Congress of U. S., to Daniel Singer, FAS, re research conducted or supported by Federal Government [phc]; reply, 1/31/1964 [cc], 2/4/1964 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., University of Maryland, to R.R.W., C. U., re developments on FAS contacts with U. S. House of Representatives Select Committee on Government Research [tls], 2/14/1964 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., University of Maryland, to R.R.W., C. U., re forthcoming conference "Transition to a Peacetime Economy" [tls], 2/24/1964 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., University of Maryland, from R.R.W., re letter from Bernard R. Carman requesting text of resolution introduced and adopted at Council meeting in January [cc], B. R. C. to R.R.W., 3/9/1964 [tls], 3/19/1964 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., URA, from R.R.W., re recent letter [tls], 5/4/1990 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., URA, from R.R.W., re re-election as Overseer-At-Large on Fermilab Board of Overseers [tls], 4/30/1992 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., URA, to "Members of the URA Boards of Trustees and Overseers," re SSC vote in Congress [fax], J. S. T. to "Presidents and Chancellors of URS Universities," re SSC vote in Congress [fax], Paul F. Slattery, University of Rochester, to Daniel P. Moynihan, U. S. Senate, re SSC vote [fax], 6/18/1992 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., URA, to "Members of the Board of Trustees, Members of the SSC Board of Overseers, Members of the Fermilab Board of Overseers," re "orderly termination of the SSC" [fax], DOE News, statement by Secretary of Energy Hazel R. O'Leary regretting closure of SSC [fax], 10/21/1993 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Toll, John S., URA, to R.R.W., C. U., re resignation from URA [pls], announcement of search for URS President [pi], doodle on verso; reply, 1/2/1994, draft [al], draft [phc], 12/16/1993 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Tollestrup, Alvin V., C. I. T., to R.R.W., C. U., re loan of Monte Carlo study of showers, now being returned, machine is up to 16 MEV [tls], 11/5/1955 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Tollestrup, Alvin V., Fermilab, re arranging small meeting to discuss possibility of doing experiments using colliding beams at Fermilab [tls], 1/15/1976 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Tollestrup, Alvin V.: R.R.W. to Jane Materazzo, AAAS (American Academy of Arts and Sciences), re nomination of A. V. T. for membership in the Academy [phc], 10/22/1986 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Tollestrup, Alvin V.: R.R.W. to Dr. David Kleppner, M. I. T., re support for nomination of A. V. T. for membership in National Academy of Science [pl], support statement by R.R.W., 8/1994 [pm], Diane Sellinger for Dr. Leon M. Lederman, to R.R.W., Ithaca, 8/3/1994, re 'Seconding the Nomination" [pls], L. M. L. to Particle and Fields Member," re supporting A. V. T. [phc], proposal for nomination by L. M. L. [phc], statement on A. T. by L. M. L. [phc], 8/12/1994 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Tolman, Richard C., Committee on Post War Policy, to R.R.W., re technical aspects of appropriate post war policy for research and development [tls]; reply, 10/6/1944 [cc], 9/29/1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Toohig, Timothy E., Fermilab, to R.R.W., C. U., re report on visit to Dubna [tls], 12/28/1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Toohig, Timothy E., SSC, to Dr. John S. Toll, URA, re situation in former Soviet Union [phc], article "Use of the Protvino Accelerator Complex in Support of SSC" [phc], 4/2/1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Toohig, Timothy E.: clipping from Fort Worth Star Telegram, 1/24/1993 [phc], note to Bob and Jane from Bob [als], 2/9/1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Toohig, Timothy E., Dallas, to R.R.W., re connections between physics and spirituality [pls], 6/7/1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Toohig, Timothy E., Boston College, to Jane, re availability of her book, nice tribute for Bob at MGH [als], 10/4/1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Toohig, Timothy E., to Bob and Jane, re thanks for sending material, offered to go to Novosibirsk [Christmas card], December, [1995] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Townes, Charles H., Secretary of Energy Advisory Board, to James D. Watkins, Department of Energy, re report of meeting, outlines recommendations [phc], notes on verso [am], 10/1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Travis, John W., Topeka, KS, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re request to copy Del Regato lecture for volume to be published [pls], note on recto [am], 12/28/1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Trilling, George H., Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory, to R.R.W., C. U., re congratulations on winning Fermi Award [pls], 12/11/1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Triolo, Roberto, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, to R.R.W., re future Fermilab [printed form, completed by hand], 9/6/1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Trivelpiece, Alvin W., AAAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re SSC [pls], 5/22/1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Trivelpiece, Alvin W., Oak Ridge National Laboratory, to R.R.W., Ithaca re giving Weinberg Lecture [pls]; A. W. T., to R.R.W., 3/19/1996 re lecture [pls]; A. W. T., to R.R.W., 5/24/1996 thanks [pls]; Nancy Gray to R.R.W., 5/31/1996, re talk [als], 2/22/1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Trousdale, J. B., C. U., from R.R.W., C. U., re improved operation of LNS [cc, signed]; reply, 6/6/1953 [tls], 6/4/1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Truppin, Andrea, The Voyager Company, to R.R.W., re CD-ROM on film "The Day After Trinity" [fax], 4/26/1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tsipis, Kosta, The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re 10/1991 meeting of Board of Directors of Bulletin and plan to review purpose, editorial policy, and tenor of Bulletin in relation to end of Cold War [pls]; reply, 4/2/1992; K. T. to R.R.W., 4/7/1992, further reply [pls], 2/5/1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Tu, Jun-sheng, Academia Sinica, to R.R.W., FAS, re American scientists visiting China and hostile attitude of U. S. government toward China (2 copies in English, 1 in Chinese) [phc]; reply, 4/30/1964, 1 copy in English, 1 copy in Chinese [phc], 1 copy in English [cc], 3/6/1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tu, Jun-sheng, Academia Sinica, from R.R.W., FAS, re international climate, continuing desire for scientific cooperation between U. S. and China, 1 copy in English, 1 copy in Chinese [phc]; reply, 11/28/1964, 1 copy in English, 1 copy in Chinese [phc], 9/22/1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tunnell, R. M., ONR, to R.R.W., C. U., re announcement of vacancy in office [tls], announcement [pi], 5/6/1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Turkevich, John, Princeton University, to R.R.W., re invitation to affiliate with Princeton Chapter of Sigma Xi [tls], 10/10/1941 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Turner, Clarence, University of Wisconsin, to Dr. Edward Creutz, Princeton University, re separation of U235 [als], 1/8/1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Turner, Michael S., Aspen center for Physics, to "Dear Trustee Member," re land acquisition [pl], 3/23/1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Uehling, Edwin A., National Research Council, to R.R.W., C. U., re conference on problems of energy loss suffered by heavy and light charged particles passing through matter [tls]; reply, 2/19/1958 [cc], 2/6/1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Unschalm, E., to R.R.W., re Miguel [als], 7/18/1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Urey, Harold C., Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, to R.R.W., C. U., re request to be sponsor of dinner for Condon [telegram]; reply, 3/15/1948 [telegram], 3/15/1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Urey, Harold C., Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists (Eileen C. Fry for H. C. U.), to R.R.W., C. U., re sponsorship of dinner, arrangement for speakers at dinner [tls], 3/25/1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Urey, Harold C., Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, to R.R.W., C. U., re International Conference of scientists [tls], 4/16/1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Van Atta, C. M., University of Southern California, Los Angeles (UCLA), to R.R.W., re building a cyclotron, requests information and drawings [tls], 3/30/1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Van Hove, Leon, CERN, to R.R.W., best wishes, visit to Fermilab [als], 12/22/1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Varro, Paul, Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re subscribing [tls], notes in shorthand on recto [als], 5/12/1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Veksler, V. I., Lebedev Institute of Physics, from R.R.W., re preparing way for uphcoming visit to Russia of Gerard Piel, Scientific American, hopes to see him in July at Geneva conference [cc]; reply, 1/31/1960 [tls]; R.R.W. to V. I. V., 5/2/1960, further reply [cc], 2/6/1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Veksler, V. I., Joint Institute for Nuclear Research, from R.R.W., re copy of reprint, hopes to establish exchange with Russian physicists, lab news [cc], 10/28/1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Veksler, V. I., Joint Institute for Nuclear Research, to R.R.W., C. U., re upcoming conference on problems connected with experiments with electrons and photons [tls], 7/29/1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Veksler to I. L. Turkevich, re mutual visits to accelerators in U. S. and Russia, translation from Russian [cc], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vigneaud, Vincent du, C. U. Medical College, to R.R.W., re congratulations on election to National Academy [tls], 4/24/1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vineyard, George, Columbia University, from R.R.W. and Wonyong Lee, re notes used in presentation to G. V., Nick Samios, and Kjell Johnsen at BNL [phc], 4/21/1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vineyard, George, BNL, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re recent letter, ideas on AUI-BNL [tls], 9/24/1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Volkoff, George, University of British Columbia, to R.R.W., re Monte Carlo method [tls]; reply, 3/29/1950 [cc], 3/8/1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Volkoff, G. M., University of British Columbia, to R.R.W., C. U., re offer of magnet and doughnut, invitation to visit, questions on accelerator and costs [tls]; reply, 8/8/1963 [cc], 7/22/1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - von Eugen, F., Excerpta Medica, to R.R.W., re becoming subscriber [tls], 4/16/1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - von Hippel, Frank, FAS, to R.R.W., re proposal for "Unilateral Two-Year Moratorium on U.S. Production of Plutonium for Nuclear Weapons" [tls], "The Plutonium Challenge: an Open Letter to the President and the Congress of the United States" [phc], 9/28/1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wadsworth, James J., Citizens Committee for a Nuclear Test Ban Treaty, to R.R.W., C. U., re thanks for supporting ratification of Atomic Test Ban Treaty [tls], 10/7/1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wagner, Philip M., The Sun, Baltimore, to R.R.W., re science and freedom, science in Russia [tls], P. M. W. to Dr. [Freeman] Dyson, 5/13/1956 [cc], newspaper articles [phc], 6/26/1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wakerling, R. K., UCB, to R.R.W., Santa Fe, re making tape of isotron article for transcription [tls], 8/17/1946 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wakerling, R. K., UCB, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re isotron article transcript [tls]; reply, 10/7/1946 [cc], 9/27/1946 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Waldhauer, Fred, Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc., to "Engineers Interested in E. A. T.," re setting up collaboration between artists and engineers [phc], "Organization of Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc." [phc], 4/24/1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Walker, Darcy, University of Birmingham, U. K., to R.R.W., re working at Cornell [tls], 6/8/1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Walker, Darcy, University of Birmingham, U. K., to R.R.W., re reprint order, visiting U. S., progress at Birmingham proton sychrotron slow, needs equipment [als], 7/17/1951 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Walker, Darcy, University of Birmingham, U. K., to R.R.W., C. U., re did get job in Birmingham, teaching graduate course on experimental high energy physics, saw Glasgow synchrotron [tls]; reply, 10/8/1952 [cc], 9/24/1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Walker, Gordon, Rutherford Appleton Laboratory, to R. R. W, Ithaca, re MacRobert Award, 1995 [tls], "The Development of Superconducting Particle Colliders" [pi], 3/30/1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Walker, Harry, Boston, from R.R.W., C. U., re speaking engagements, [cc, signed]; H. W. to R.R.W., 11/13/1964, renewing request [tls]; reply, 12/17/1964 [cc], 10/10/1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)